Hi, in this lesson, give a little about Engine Planning Mode in Google Antigravity.
This is a mode you will use when you need Engine to handle compact stars, can require
careful planning and careful execution.
So let's start with this Engine Mode.
As you see, the documentation is not provided to much information, it might be complex from
a first look, but I will try to structure everything to use it, you will understand how
to use it right.
So, Engine Planning Mode is designed for quality and so when you activate this mode, the
Engine takes time to blend before executing your task.
It's perfect when you need a deeper search, some complex implementations or some collaborative
work where the Engine needs to sync through multiple steps before taking an action.
So, Planning Mode works best for complex stars, that involve in multiple files.
We should require some careful consideration or need some structured approach.
For example, adding new features, the touch, a lot of files, your code base, the refactor
and architecture or implementing of course some complex business logic.
This is a task where taking extra time to blend upfront saves the time fixing mistakes
later.
So, as the Engine Deal organized it worked, research your code base and execute with optimal
quality.
So, let's now talk about use cases and I will show you its own practice.
For example, you can refactor an existing code.
Sometimes I need to restrict your code for better maintainability, for instance you might
want to separate like your calendar class into smaller parts, imagine it's a big class
and no one 500 lines of code and you'd like to separate it.
So, you can ask AI and plan what to do it.
You can implement complex business logic.
If you'd like to add some validation rules to calendar, you'd like to support different
calendar dates for different locations and etc.
You can also use plan what for it.
You can use it for adding new features with multiple files.
Oh, let's take it into example.
So, you might want to deal with the current month as a grid with weak names and days.
Like, imagine a table when you open a date picker with a weak name, so you see the structured
dates in the provided column under the weak name.
So, and we're going to implement it.
So, just make sure the planning mode is selected here.
And now we can ask it.
So, we'll type this with the current month as a grid with weak numbers and days of the
month.
So, it will provide some HTML from the method for us.
Yeah, and we of course hope it will create multiple methods.
It will have a good structure to be able to reuse it later.
So, when the press enter and what's the edge and sync, it will sync about our request.
It will eliminate some existing files we already have.
The calendar and helper.js to understand our current structure.
I'll start and we'll explain you in parallel how it works.
The plan mode follows the clear workflow that keeps you in control on every stage.
The first the edges will request and eliminate your existing code base.
It creates the implementation plan cost.
So, first it's a research the code base and the next step it creates implementation plan.
It creates implementation plan as artifact.
This plan outlines what the edge and intends to do, which files that you create, modify,
and what approach it would take.
So, after it will be created, you see it was already done and it asks us to review it.
This review it and then we can process it.
So, if you close it, we can always click open it or we can click artifacts and find it here.
So, as artifacts, it files as that edge and create during the work with you here,
during the planning during different tasks.
So, we now can review this plan.
Yes, we see the display as the current month as agreed with week-long names and days of the month.
Okay, proposal changes.
In calendar, we will add the getdays and months method.
Yeah, it's so logical.
You'll add get first day of the month method, update render method.
Okay, so details the week names are this, so if I'd like to change the implementation plan,
I can add a comments.
I just select the part of the text, yeah, and for example, I'd like to start a week from
a Monday, start from Monday, and I will consider our comments.
Okay, the verification view verifies the logic variant test script, but with you create
the test script, view verify all logic works and then the script will be removed.
We can create a small test script, it imports the class, okay, it's fine, let's check
out might be with like to, let's might be Monday, okay, let's click review and add optional
comment, some additional comment, display, display and the top, all storm, oh, what we'd like?
The months, the month's name, we can click submit, so the implementation plan starts.
So let's just see, so it can fit me in implementation details, it's syncing, so as we see
it updates the implementation plan and we again can review it, so we see the week names
start from Monday, it's good, so and we also should see some words, display federal
with the weekdays, display the days of the month's, where is the month's name at the top?
Okay, display at the top of the table, the month's name at the top of the grid.
Okay, so every time, if we don't like something plan, we can add a comment, add a review,
do the review, so we can verify it, we won't be finalized as we want, okay, it is processing
our request, okay, let's wait a bit, so it's finished.
And display, oh no, it's not yet finished, okay, it's processing still, oops, I think
I clicked not updates the plan, but it might be, yeah, I think I clicked already updates
the code, not the right button, but you know, you can still do it in the comments and
doing the review, the next step after you press an enter or press the proceed button, the
plan mode, so it will proceed with the implementation plan, and you can of course review
and some pending actions, if it will be popping up, so for example, there are some task
groups, if the plan is big, yeah, you see the task groups like the helper methods, and
the next one is rendering, yeah, and you might see it here, you of course need to expand
it, and you see, you can see the start, you can see the files were edited, you can open
the div only for the start group, so it was done for, to simplify the review, don't
review all the code at one time, but reviewed by small pieces, so and you can verify
what a helper matters, give us edit, and how we, how he implemented, let's close the
div, and how he implemented the render method, so the buttons this lesson, we want to
verify it, so, but it's of course really important, so then he asks us to verify the document,
yeah, and at the bottom, might be some pending actions, for example, if it will need to
create a file, if it need to rename some file, he might ask you, okay, I'd like to rename
this file, can you approve it, or declare it, yeah, and use some time, it's need to be
aware of it, and just monitor it, sometimes it requires an action from you, okay, so let's
wrap up, you can use plain mode when task is complex, involve multiple files, so you can
click of course accept all changes, yeah, as it added a method, as it added the render
method, but my recommendation is always to review it, always ask a lot of questions if you
don't understand how something to work, if you'll see it might be implemented easier,
you can also ask to refactor it, because really often a I do the small steps to implement
something, sometimes it's been lazy, and you might need few more iterations to make your
code, not perfect but better, more performant, so as a main benefit of plain mode is quality
and control, as you can create a plan, you can review it, you can add a common review
it again, you can work in organized task groups as you see here, yeah, you can review each
task group, so you can, if you need to create to delete some files, you will have some
ending actions, you also hear in control, so and it's really good for some complex tasks,
of course the trade-off is speeds, you might spend more time on with a plan mode, we
are leaving the comments for the plan, but you will win at the end, you will have a better
implementation, and so you will have more expected implementation, so of course, so I recommend
you to use it for some features, some refactoring code for big changes, and don't forget
always verify and review a code AI, give you always tested, you can also have to test it,
and see you in the next lesson.